[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I already
published 62 YouTube videos covering
beginners level intermed level and
advanced level concepts of trien Tas
from couple of videos onwards I've
started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of
obstacles and how can we solve those
obstacles while automating your test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos this is our lesson 63 in terms of
overall tricentis TSA automation
training and this is obstacle 21 in
terms of real time scenarios in this
lesson I'm going to teach you how can we
solve an obstacle where you need to
interact with a dynamic web table and
you need to search for a specific cell
value in this particular Dynamic web
table by using constraint print action
mode and by using search table cell
value methods so now let us see in
detail what is the obstacle that we need
to solve
for this is the obstacle list and this
is our obstacle that we are working on
the name of obstacle is table search and
which is categorized as hard let us go
for
it so let us see what is the obstacle
enter true or false depending on whether
the table contains a cell with value 15
you see the below table let's see if you
have any value 15 here so in the cells I
do not see a value 15 any in any of the
cell so that's why I'm going to enter as
false see as soon as you enter false you
solve the automation problem now let me
try
again so this time again I don't see any
15 value in any of in any of the cell so
that's why again I'm going to enter as
false so let me try again now you can
see here there is value 15 in one of the
cell so this table is dynamic and all
the values are dynamic DC in the table
so now I can just enter
true so that means to solve this problem
you need to search for a specific value
in each row and each colum so how can we
achieve this for for that let us go to
trentos as usual we're going to scan the
objects that are required to automate
the scenario this is my obstacle folder
I'm in modules section right click in
right click on obstacle folder select
scan
application now this is the application
that I would like to select and click on
scan so now to automate this particular
scenario we need to add this web table
and also you need to add the text box
correct so if you can see here this is
my web table select the web
table and then you can select the text
box also where we'll be entering the
true or false so now you can see these
two objects are uniquely identified you
can see here selected item is unique in
the same way table also selected item is
unique now let me name the module as
obstacle 41 0 36 this is my obstacle
name let me copy this
obstacle let's copy the
obstacle and then name the module with
the same obstacle
name and then save the
module now now close the X
scan so let us go back to trient tasa
and you can see here the latest module
whatever we added this is the latest
module
41036 double click on this so you can
see these two objects that we added so
now let us go back to our test case
section the blue section we are creating
the test cases under folder obstacle
right so all these test cases that we
already worked on almost like 20
obstacles now right click on this folder
and select create test case and name
this test case with the same obstacle
name now double click on this test case
so to automate your
scenario drag the module that we scanned
and dropped on and drop onto test
case let's expand
this so here
what is
the step that we need to follow so what
is our first step I need to First search
for number
15 in every row and every column of this
particular web table how can we do that
so to search number 15 and filter out
all other values or filter out all other
cell values you have to use
constraint mode so I have already
published another video on constraint
mode how can we use constraint mode in
our in my previous video sessions I
would recommend you guys to visit those
sessions so now let us go back to the
trient stasa and here under cell what I
would like to use here I would like to
use the constraint option so if this
cell has a value of
15 I would like to I don't want to
verify this instead I would like to
introduce a
constraint One Thing If You observe I'm
not providing any row number here
because I would like to verify this
value of 15 in every row and every cell
correct so that's why I'm not providing
any value here I'm simply entering the
value 15 and action mode constraint what
it does it goes every row by row and
every cell it searches for the
15 if it exists right then it considers
that particular row so whenever it finds
let's say in this particular example
when it comes to row 15 sorry when it
comes to Row three it verifies each row
sorry it verifies each cell and that
means at Row
three tricentis will be able to identify
the value 15 that means is using the
constraint it filters out rest of the
rows as soon as it reaches this 15 row
now I would like to store one value here
I would like to validate one thing what
if this row exists that
means the row containing the cell value
15 okay if that exist then I would like
to store that into a buffer I'm going to
make this as bore
result and here I would like to change
the action mode as
buffer so what happens it
first takes the row
one it then verifies if any of the cell
in row one contains 15 it does not
because I'm using constraint mode then
again it goes to row
two it does not contain 15 so it filters
out and then it goes to row three and it
verifies each and every cell value then
it finds
the 15 value in the cell that means it
considers this particular row now if
this Row the third row exists value 15
right now I'm instructing tasa if row
exists with value 15
then store the result exists true or
false result into a buffer called bore
result right so in this case I'm going
to get exists as true for the row three
right I would like
to enter the result true or fault result
into this particular text box that's why
I'm going to call the above buff buffer
whatever we are storing here to call the
buffer open curly braces capital B open
Square braces Capital bore result this
is
my buffer name close Square braces close
curly
braces done
now let's save the test case and change
the work state change the work state as
completed and
now let's run the test
case with the existing values here right
for this particular
scenario it should return True Value and
it should enter true right let me right
click and run in
scratchbook it entered true because it
finds a row with value 15 hence it
returns as true let's go here now I can
see
here see it received value of
true so if I go here I can see
here the bore result has been set to
Value true now let me just try again
okay let me try
again so here now you can see I don't
have value 50 I would like to run the
test case again and see if I return the
value of false right click and run
scratchbook
it searches see now the value has been
entered as false you can see here it
searched the first row could not find 15
value by using constraint it filters out
it searches second row it could not find
15 value it filters out and third row it
could not find it filters out that means
the row exists will be false
hence it entered the value as false so
this is how you can search the value
within the table cell by using
constraint mode and with the combination
of buffer to enter the result in edit
box if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries
hope you all understand how can we solve
an obstacle where you need to interact
with the dynamic web table and you need
to search a specific table cell
value without knowing the specific
column and without knowing a specific
row by using the constant action modes
and search table C value
methods please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos and don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]